<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE chapter PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN" "http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd">
<chapter id="sid-2654310">
    
    <title>Gateway Bindings</title>
    <section id="sid-2654309">
      
      <title>Camel Bindings</title>
      <para>Camel binding support in SwitchYard allows Camel components to be used as gateway bindings for services and references within an application.</para>
      <important>
        <para>NOTE: The primary focus of Camel integration in 0.1 was the use of the core EIP routing engine within Camel as a service implementation.  Testing for Camel bindings was limited to the Camel File component in 0.1, but this will be expanded considerably in 0.2.  If you run into an issue with a specific Camel component in SwitchYard, please let us know in the SwitchYard forum.</para>
        <para>
          <ulink url="http://community.jboss.org/en/switchyard?view=discussions"/>
        </para>
      </important>
      <section id="sid-2654309_CamelBindings-BindingServiceswithCamel">
        
        <title>Binding Services with Camel</title>
        <para>
          Composite-level services can be bound to a Camel component using the
          <code>&lt;binding.camel&gt;</code>
          binding definition.  The following configuration options are available for
          <code>binding.camel</code>
          :
        </para>
        <itemizedlist>
          <listitem>
            <para>
              <code>configURI</code>
              : contains the Camel endpoint URI used to configure a Camel component instance
            </para>
          </listitem>
          <listitem>
            <para>
              <code>operationSelector</code>
              : specification of the operation name to use for the message exchange.  If the target service only has a single operation, this setting is optional.
            </para>
          </listitem>
        </itemizedlist>
        <para>Here's an example of what a service binding looks like using a Camel component.</para>
        <informalexample>
          <programlisting>&lt;sca:composite&gt;
    &lt;sca:service name="SimpleCamelService" promote="SimpleComponent/SimpleCamelService"&gt;
        &lt;camel:binding.camel configURI="file://target/input?fileName=test.txt&amp;amp;initialDelay=50&amp;amp;delete=true"&gt;
            &lt;camel:operationSelector operationName="print"/&gt;
        &lt;/camel:binding.camel&gt;
    &lt;/sca:service&gt;
    &lt;!-- sca:component definition omitted --&gt;
&lt;/sca:composite&gt;</programlisting>
        </informalexample>
      </section>
      <section id="sid-2654309_CamelBindings-BindingReferenceswithCamel">
        
        <title>Binding References with Camel</title>
        <para>Binding a reference with Camel is very similar to binding a service.  The only significant difference is that specification of the operationSelector is not required on reference bindings.</para>
        <informalexample>
          <programlisting>&lt;sca:composite&gt;
    &lt;sca:reference name="WarehouseService" promote="OrderComponent/WarehouseService"&gt;
        &lt;camel:binding.camel configURI="file://target/output"/&gt;
    &lt;/sca:reference&gt;
&lt;/sca:composite&gt;</programlisting>
        </informalexample>
      </section>
    </section>
    <section id="sid-2654311">
      
      <title>SOAP Bindings</title>
      <para>The SOAP component in SwitchYard provides SOAP-based web service binding support for services and references in SwitchYard.</para>
      <section id="sid-2654311_SOAPBindings-BindingServiceswithSOAP">
        
        <title>Binding Services with SOAP</title>
        <para>
          Composite-level services can be exposed as a SOAP-based web service using the
          <code>&lt;binding.soap&gt;</code>
          binding definition.  The following configuration options are available for
          <code>binding.soap</code>
          when binding services:
        </para>
        <itemizedlist>
          <listitem>
            <para>
              <code>wsdl</code>
              : location of the WSDL used to describe the web service endpoint.  A relative path can be used if the WSDL is included in the deployed application.  If the WSDL is located outside the application, then a
              <code>file:</code>
              or
              <code>http:</code>
              URL can be used.
            </para>
          </listitem>
          <listitem>
            <para>
              <code>serverPort</code>
              : port number that the HTTP service should bind to for the SOAP endpoint.  Defaults to 8080 if unspecified.
            </para>
          </listitem>
          <listitem>
            <para>
              <code>port</code>
              : port name in the WSDL to use.  If unspecified, the first port definition in the WSDL is used for the service endpoint
            </para>
          </listitem>
        </itemizedlist>
        <important>
          <para>The default port of the SOAP binding conflicts with the default listener on JBoss AS, so you must specify a unique port in your configuration when deploying to JBoss AS.  Tighter integration with JBoss WS is planned to eliminate this annoying constraint.</para>
        </important>
        <para>Here's an example of what a SOAP service binding looks like:</para>
        <informalexample>
          <programlisting>&lt;sca:composite name="orderApp"&gt;
    &lt;sca:service name="OrderService" promote="OrderService"&gt;
        &lt;soap:binding.soap&gt;
            &lt;soap:wsdl&gt;wsdl/OrderService.wsdl&lt;/soap:wsdl&gt;
            &lt;soap:serverPort&gt;9000&lt;/soap:serverPort&gt;        
         &lt;/soap:binding.soap&gt;
    &lt;/sca:service&gt;
&lt;/sca:composite&gt;</programlisting>
        </informalexample>
      </section>
      <section id="sid-2654311_SOAPBindings-BindingReferenceswithSOAP">
        
        <title>Binding References with SOAP</title>
        <para>
          Binding a reference with SOAP can be used to make SOAP-based web services available to SwitchYard services. The following configuration options are available for
          <code>binding.soap</code>
          when binding references:
        </para>
        <itemizedlist>
          <listitem>
            <para>
              <code>wsdl</code>
              : location of the WSDL used to describe the web service endpoint.   A relative path can be used if the WSDL is included in the deployed  application.  If the WSDL is located outside the application, then a
              <code>file:</code>
              or
              <code>http:</code>
              URL can be used.
            </para>
          </listitem>
          <listitem>
            <para>
              <code>port</code>
              : port name in the WSDL to use.  If unspecified, the first port definition in the WSDL is used for the service endpoint.
            </para>
          </listitem>
        </itemizedlist>
        <informalexample>
          <programlisting>&lt;sca:composite&gt;
    &lt;sca:reference name="WarehouseService" promote="OrderComponent/WarehouseService"&gt;
        &lt;camel:binding.camel configURI="file://target/output"/&gt;
    &lt;/sca:reference&gt;
&lt;/sca:composite&gt;</programlisting>
        </informalexample>
      </section>
    </section>
  </chapter>
