<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE chapter PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN" "http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd">
<chapter id="sid-2654315">
    
    <title>Deployment</title>
    <section id="sid-2654315_Deployment-AvailableRuntimes">
      
      <title>Available Runtimes</title>
      <para>The 0.1 release of SwitchYard supports the following deployment options:</para>
      <itemizedlist>
        <listitem>
          <para>JBoss Application Server 6.0 Final</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>JBoss Application Server 7.0 Beta 3</para>
        </listitem>
      </itemizedlist>
      <para>At present, you must use the SwitchYard distribution of AS6 or AS7 with SwitchYard pre-installed.  Future releases of SwitchYard will add support for additional runtimes and the option for installing SwitchYard in an existing application server.</para>
    </section>
    <section id="sid-2654315_Deployment-JBossAS6.0">
      
      <title>JBoss AS 6.0</title>
      <para>Deployment on JBoss AS6 is the same old, same old.  Simply copy your SwitchYard application to the the server's deploy directory and the SwitchYard deployer will take care of the rest.</para>
      <informalexample>
        <programlisting>cp myapp.jar $JBOSS_HOME/server/default/deploy/.</programlisting>
      </informalexample>
      <para>Undeploying a SwitchYard application is equally unsurprising.  Just remove the app jar from the deploy directory like so:</para>
      <informalexample>
        <programlisting>rm $JBOSS_HOME/server/default/deploy/myapp.jar</programlisting>
      </informalexample>
    </section>
    <section id="sid-2654315_Deployment-JBossAS7.0">
      
      <title>JBoss AS 7.0</title>
      <para>
        Things are a bit different in JBoss AS7.  Auto-deploy still exists, but there are some subtle changes to the process.  Deploy is still just a matter of copying the archive to the server, but the target directory should be
        <code>standalone/deployments</code>
        .
      </para>
      <informalexample>
        <programlisting>cp myapp.jar $JBOSS_HOME/standalone/deployments/.</programlisting>
      </informalexample>
      <para>
        To undeploy the application, you need to remove the
        <code>.deployed</code>
        marker file that is generated upon successful deployment of your application:
      </para>
      <informalexample>
        <programlisting>rm $JBOSS_HOME/standalone/deployments/myapp.jar.deployed</programlisting>
      </informalexample>
      <para>
        You can find more information on the ins and outs of deployment on JBoss AS7 in the
        <code>README.txt</code>
        file contained in the standalone/deployments directory of the distribution.
      </para>
    </section>
  </chapter>
